A Guide to the Berkeley Family Papers
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #38-113-d
Berkeley Family Papers 1859-1985
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
38-113-d
83 items
Mary Randolph Berkeley
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
This material was made a gift to the Library by Miss Mary Randolph Berkeley of Charlottesville, Virginia through Edmund Berkeley, Jr., on April 26, 1989.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of 83 items, 1859 (1963-1985), chiefly pertaining to Norborne Berkeley and the Berkeley family. Correspondence, 1973-1975, between Mary Randolph Berkeley and W. Hugh Peal, president of the Loudoun County Historical Society, concerns her gift of her grandfather Norborne Berkeley's silk wedding vest; related newspaper clippings, 1974-1975, are included. The genealogy correspondence, 1938 and 1944, and 1969-1985, pertains mainly to Norborne Berkeley but also contains information on other members of the family. Papers of the Iglehart and Waddell families include a letter, April 20, 1859, from E. D. Waddell to her granddaughter, Anne H. Waddell; a statement on the death of Waddell Iglehart on February 6, 1873; and, a handwritten copy of the Iglehart family bible records. Among the personal papers of Mary Randolph Berkeley are a letter, April 12, 1963, from The Seven Society; a Society of the Purple Shadows invitation and thank you, 1967; and, a passport issued in 1973.
Container List
- Correspondence of Mary Randolph Berkeley and W. Hugh Peal of the Loudoun County Historical Society, and related papers re Norborne Berkeley's wedding vest, 1973-1975; 13 items
- Genealogy Correspondence of Mary Randolph Berkeley, 1969-1985; 9 items
- Genealogy Correspondence of William Noland Berkeley (electrostatic copies), 1938, 1944; 18 items
- Genealogy Papers re the Berkeley family, ca. 1905-1982; 20 items
- Papers of the Iglehart and Waddell families, 1859, 1873; 3 items
- Personal Papers of Mary Randolph Berkeley, 1963-1973; 7 items
- Photograph of Norborne Berkeley (copy portrait in the Virginia Historical Society), n.d.; 1 item
- Postcards and Publications on Berkeley Castle and Bristol Cathedral, 10 items
- "Berkeley of Barn Elms"--genealogical chart compiled by William Clayton Torrence, 1912; 1 item (Box Oversize)
- Berkeley Coat of Arms, n.d.; 1 item (Box Oversize)